别走啊
Hold it
小心啊
Be careful
来，小心，我扶你！
Come, be careful, give me your hand
谢谢你啊
Thank you
过来
This way
喂喂喂！小朋友
Hey kids...
过来
Come here
干什么啊？
What?
来
Come
你知不知道这里不可以踢球的？
Do you know that you can't play soccer here?
好危险的嘛！
It's very dangerous
那边有车，这边有车，那边也有车
There are cars coming from different directions
别在这里踢了，把球还你！
Don't play here, here is your ball
到球场那边踢
Go play in a playground
去那边踢了
Let's go play over there
好吧
Okay
好讨厌啊
You slut...
喂，这边
This way
好坏啊，别搞啊
You are mean, stop it
这里，来啊
This way, come here
快点啊，过来啊
Come over here, quick
Hi...豪哥...Hi
Ho...
喂，你先走开！
You go first
豪哥！
Ho, I am going to swim with Wan
豪哥，我先下去陪慧姐游泳了！       去啦...去啦
Go then...
哇，你都好厉害啊，大白天的火气这么大
God, why do you turn on so easily in daytime?
说不定他吃了“伟哥”呢
I think he must have eaten "Viagra"
喂，不关我事的啊
It's nothing to do with me
她是出了名的“潘金莲”，我受不了的嘛！
You know? She is bitchy
喂，鸡雄，那你不是做了“西门庆”？
Slut Hung, you're a sex slave
西门庆、西门庆
Sex slave...
救命呀...抽筋呀...救命呀
Help! I am cramping! Help!
不用怕
Don't be scared!
不用怕...我在这
Don't be scared! I am here with you
我没有怕啊...我最怕你不紧张我嘛
I am not scared, I just worry that you don't care about me
我告诉你，我一辈子最紧张的只有两个人
Let me tell you In my life, I only worry about two persons
一个就是你，一个就是我老妈
One is you, the other is my mother
我知道啊，我作弄你一下嘛！
I know, I am just playing with you
慢慢玩吧，我有事谈！        嗯！
Enjoy yourself, we have things to do
车准备好没有？
Is the car ready?
搞定了
Yes, the car is ready
车子全部用树叶遮住了，油和水都好了！
I have covered the car, everything is set
随时都可以行动
We can start anytime
家伙呢？
And the guns?
全部检查过了，没问题！
I have checked them, no problem
强，放来看下！
Ken, show it to me
好的
Okay
他每天早上8点由司机开车离开家里
His driver picks him up at eight every morning
他的行车路线是沿着睦诚道
His car will move along the Moorsom Road...
转右去大坑道
turn right to Tai Hang Road
跟着左转到福群道口
And then left turn to Fuk Kwan Avenue
再转右上大坑道天桥
And turn right to Tai Hang Road flyover
去铜锣湾，上天桥到湾仔北
Then the car will move from Causeway Bay to Wanchai North
在港湾道左转，停在海港商场
Then turn left to the Harbour Road and stop at the Harbour Arcade
如果没意外的话,应该在8点35分到达办公室
If everything goes right he should arrive at 8:35am at his office
好！我们明天早上陪他吃早餐
Okay! We will go have breakfast with him tomorrow
(Lee's villa at Deep Water Bay)
鸡雄，你那边什么环境啊？
Slut Hung, what about you?
可以的，不过没女人看而已
Everything is good but there is no girl around
豪哥，8点了，他应该出门口了
Ho, it is eight He should be leaving soon
不用紧张，还有大把时间呢
Chill out, we have plenty of time
豪哥，有警察
Ho, there are cops
怎么办？
What are we going to do?
警察就警察咯，没见过吗？
You haven't seen a cop before? Take it easy
他开罚单呀！
Ho, he is writing a parking ticket
交通警察当然是开罚单的啊
That is his job
不然还可以做什么？
What else do you want him to do?
再见
Bye
你“干哥哥”出来了，收没收到？阿强
Ken, target is appearing, over
豪哥，出来了！
Ho, he is coming out
那警察还没走
The cop is still there
让我干掉他
Let me kill him
慢着
Wait
为什么？
Why?
我们要钱，不是要命
We want money, not life
豪哥呀！
Ho
神经病！
You are nuts
喂，报案中心吗？这里是深水湾高尔夫球会呀！
Is it 999? This is a call from the Deep Water Bay Golf Club
我见到一个婆婆被货车撞倒！
I saw an old lady who has been hit by a truck
喂！快点把婆婆拉出来给她止血呀！
You need to send help right now
TAPI，位置是深水湾道高尔夫球会
TAPl, location is Deep Water Bay Golf Club
有谁在附近？
Any one around?
87371收到
87371 copy, on my way
豪哥你真棒！
Ho, you are smart
车到了！
Here comes the target
做事吧
Let's do this
下车...
Get out of the car!
下车...下车啊...
快点啊...下车...
Hurry! Get out of the car!
Now! Get out of the car
出来啊
Get Out!
不要开枪啊...不要开枪啊...
Don't kill me Go, hurry up!
快点啊...住口，别动呀！
Hurry! Get in the car, don't move!
1996年5月13日，警方发现李巨坐驾
On May 1 3, 1 996 police discovered Lee Gui's ride
你真倒霉！被我们的兄弟抓回来了
You're ill-fated to be kidnapped!
跟我进来吧！
Follow me
你迟些买红衫鱼回来煎都可以啦
You can cook later
原来他什么家伙都有的
He has everything
要不要煮雪耳糖水给你喝呀？
Do I have to make you dessert too?
你肯煮，我一定肯喝呀！
I will eat it if you cook it
听说他以前守反黑组时好棒的
I heard that he used to be tough when working with the anti-triads
不过他倒霉呀！
But he screwed up!
那一宗一亿七千万的案子他破不了
He couldn't solve that robbery case of 1 7 million
还搞到每间警察局都像厨房一样
He made each police station he was assigned to become his kitchen
之后就被人调来调去了
After that, he was transferred all over the places
真的假的？
Really?
长官！  长官！
Sir Sir  Good morning Good morning
有没有见过新调来的沙展南叔呀？
Have you seen the new transferred sergeant Uncle Nam?
他出去买东西了
He went out to buy something
买什么？
Buy what?
买菜吧！
Grocery
买菜？
Grocery?
他回来了
He is back
对不起！
Sorry
南叔
Uncle Nam
长官
Sir
没关系，我们所有人都知道你最爱吃东西的
I am sorry We all know that you love to eat
我给你介绍
Let me introduce
这是sunny
This is Sunny
南叔
Uncle Nam
先等一等
Wait
嗨！   这是阿雁
This is Ann
阿雁，你好吗？  你好
Ann, how are you? Hello!
傻豹
Pink Panther
傻豹，你好吗？  你好
Pink panther, how are you? Hello
这是兴仔！  嗨！兴仔
This is Hing Hi! Hing!
长官，如果你不介意的......
Sir, if you don't mind...
不介意，我们一群兄弟都无所谓的
Don't worry, we are easy to get along
真的？不介意就最好了
Really? That's good
我有些见面礼要送给你们的
I have gifts for you guys
看好了
Look
难得大家志同道合呀
We are all friends
热烫烫的牛腩煲呀
Hot brisket
牛腩煲呀，好吃呀
Brisket, it's good
南叔，牛腩先放好，慢慢再吃呀
Uncle Nam, let's forget the brisket first
现在有宗案子
We have a case
刚收到消息，在睦诚道发现了一辆车
This is just in we found a car on Moorsom Road
好象还开过枪
The witness said it was fired
车牌号码是CA97
The license plate is CA97
是大富商李仁的大儿子李巨坐的
It's a car of Lee Gui, son of the Billionaire Lee En
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
为什么不知道？
Why not?
邵日夫的车子是6号
Mr. Shaw Yee fu's car is number six
霍英西的车子是AA19
Mr. Fok Ying see's car is AA1 9
还有，郑二万坐的平治，未换车前是88号
Cheung Yee man's Benz is number 88
换了林肯之后是169号
Now his Lincoln's number is 1 69
真有你的呀南叔
You are something!
小意思而已
That is nothing
就是因为车子是李巨的
The car belongs to Lee Gui
他没理由和司机一起失踪的
He couldn't have disappeared with the driver at the same time
还把车子停在路边
And left the car on the side
所以上面叫我们出去看看
Our boss told us to check it out
做事吧
Let's work
是，长官
Yes, sir
先吃一块
Let me take a bite first
正点！
It's good!
他们有什么话说？
What did they say?
他们叫我把内裤带回来给你
They told me to bring the underwear back to you
之后便把我打晕了
Then I was knocked out
我醒来的时候，人已经在门口了
when I woke up, I was at the door
这条内裤有没有错？
Is that Gui's underwear?
我怎么认得呢？
How do I know?
他早上穿出去，跟晚上穿回来的都不一样的
He always comes home with a different underwear
我怎么知道？
How do I know?
你是他老婆都不知道
You are his wife
难道我知道呀？
You think I know it instead?
不如报警吧？
Let's call the cops
你傻的啊？如果要报警
Are you crazy? If we call the cops
我生多少个儿子才够呀？
I need to have more sons
我们潮洲人有什么风浪没见过？
We Chiuchou people have experienced all sorts of difficulties
开门呀！
Open the door
你见不见到那里是什么地方？
Do you know where you were?
我见不到呀，他们用枪指着我
I couldn't see they were pointing a gun at me
按住我的头
They pushed my head down
我都吓死了啊
I was very scared!
老爷…老爷
Master...
外面有个男人说知道少爷在哪里
There is a man outside saying that he knows where young master is
李先生，幸会…
Nice to meet you, Mr. Lee...
这条领带是阿巨的
That is Ah Gai's tie
对不起！我觉得这领带很漂亮
Sorry! Really like this tie
所以就戴上了
So I put it on
我哥哥他怎么样？
What happened to my elder brother?
哇…四菜一汤，很清淡啊！
Not a lot of dishes
对不起！打扰你们吃饭了
Sorry! I interrupted your dinner
我们出来做生意的，一向都很敬重江湖朋友
We businessmen always respect the triads
我就送三十万给你，算是请你们的兄弟喝茶
I will give you and your friends three hundred thousand dollars
三十万？！
Three hundred thousand?
上次我去泰国旅行
Last time I was on a trip to Thailand
我见到一个艺术家也给他三十万
I saw an artist and I gave him three hundred thousands
那你想要多少？
How much do you want?
你这么爽快！
I will be honest with you
就十亿吧
One billion!
你说什么？十亿？
What? One billion?
十亿！
One billion!
你不去抢？
Why don't you go rob?
李先生，我跟你都是抢
Mr. Lee, both you and I have been robbers
只不过大家抢的方式不一样而已
Only difference is the way we rob
你可以不给我，我可无所谓
You don't want to pay, I don't mind
我哪有那么多钱啊？大哥
I don't have that much money
时代杂志富豪榜你排第八
You rank 8th on the richest men board
老爷，外面有两位警察来找你
Master, there are two cops outside wanting to talk to you
李先生，对不起，打扰了
Mr. Lee, I am sorry for bothering
请问两位有什么事呢？
Can I help you?
我们来是想调查下今早在睦诚道发现令郎汽车的事件
We come to check your son's car which is found on Moorsom Rd
那汽车嘛……
That car...
我都跟阿巨说过很多次了
I told Ah Gui many times
那车子的波箱有问题，早就应该换了
There is something wrong with the car's transmitting
那现在令郎和司机在哪儿呢？
Where is he and the driver now?
他今天早上约了一位新加坡客人开会
He had a meeting with a Singapore client
车子坏了，所以就改乘计程车去了
They took a taxi since the car broke down
他刚刚才打电话回家说不回来吃饭
He just called and said he is not coming back for dinner
按道理，即使车子坏了
But even the car broke down
司机也应该留下来看管着车子的
the driver should stay and look after the car
可能他今天带了很多文件
Maybe he had a lot of documents today
所以叫司机帮他拿吧
So he told the driver to carry them for him
两位真是有心了，谢谢
Thanks for your concern
不用客气！没事就好了，我们走了
You're welcome! We will leave then, bye
劳驾了     打扰了
Thanks Bye
没什么事了，饭菜都凉了，我不打搅你们吃饭了
Food is getting cold I don't want to bother you anymore
我怎么样给你钱呢？
How can I pay the ransom?
干嘛不吃饭呢？
Why aren't you eating?
可能他喜欢吃湿粮，不喜欢吃干粮吧？
Maybe he doesn't like dried food
装可怜吗？
Want me to pity you?
吃吧，小狗
Eat, doggie
别乱扔啊，大哥
Stop it, big bro
吃饭啦……小狗
Eat... Come on, Doggie!
吃吧！小狗
Eat! Doggie
想耍花样啊？小狗
Want to play? Doggie
豪哥……豪哥
Boss
情况怎么样？
What happened?
今晚十一点半打电话给他
I will call him at eleven thirty tonight
通知他怎样汇钱
And tell him how to pay
发财了！太棒了
We will be rich! Yeah!
这次发大财了！
I will be super rich!
李先生，你整天没吃东西了
Mr. Lee you haven't eaten anything the whole day
请你吃只鲍鱼吧
Here, eat some abalone
你真是好口福……
You are very lucky
免得你老爸怪我饿坏你
I don't want your dad to be mad at me for not feeding you well
慢慢吃！
Eat slowly!
我今天去过你家，见过你的家人
I went to your house today and talked to your father
他们吃的都没有你吃的那么好
They don't eat as good as you
我们是很守信用的
You can trust us
只要你老爸肯付赎金
If your dad pays the ransom
我说过以后不会碰你们李家一条毛
I won't bother your family again
阿芝，湾仔第二期工程的钱付了没有？
Cindy, have we paid the 2nd payment by Waichai's project?
准备好了，星期三可以付款了
It's ready, we can pay on Wednesday
你明天打电话给承建商
Call the contractor tomorrow
说我们要延期十天八天付钱
Tell them we will pay ten days later
知道了！我明天打电话给他
Okay! I will call them tomorrow
你，计算一下总公司有多少现金
You, tell me how much cash do we have in the office
全部暂时别动
And stop anyone spending it
顺便打电话去澳洲及新加坡分公司
Call the office in Australia and Singapore
看下他们有多少现金，全部汇回来
Transfer all the cash here
知道，老板
Yes boss
好……
Okay...
澳门方面怎么样？
How is thing going in Macau?
叫兄弟们开香槟
Tell our buddies to get those champagne ready
搞定！
It's done!
放了他！
Let him go
慢慢来啊，老板
Boss, slowly
你老爸真是有信用啊
Your dad does keep his promise
我答应过以后不再碰你们李家的人
I promised that I will not bother your family again
你放心啦
You can have my words
谢谢…谢谢
Thank you...
应该是我向你老爸说谢谢
I should thank your dad
谢谢了
Thanks
快向人家道谢啊
Say thanks
谢谢…谢谢
Thank you...
（深圳某夜总会）
(A night club in Shenzhen)
大家辛苦了！喝，干杯
It's been a tough job! Cheers!
豪哥，干杯
Ho, cheers
豪哥，好久没见了，什么事这么开心啊？
Ho, why are you so happy?
妈咪，我们的妞呢？
Mamasan, where is my girl?
你真急色！
You're thirsty for sex, aren't you?
今晚你想要什么类型的女孩子招呼你？
What type of girls do you want today?
你应该知道我不喜欢这种事的
You know I am not one of them
豪哥眼中只有慧姐
Ho likes Wan only
其他女人都不看在眼内
He doesn't like anyone else
我知道！要不然？
I know! If not
我早就上了他了
I will have gone after him already
我就没时间了！还另有约会
I don't have time! I have a date
你替我好好招呼他们
Take good care of them
豪哥，我会做的啦
Ho, I will
妈咪，一定要给我找个大胸的
Mamasan, I want a big breast
知道了，找一个大得撑破你的嘴
I know, I will find the biggest one for you
好呀！撑破你的嘴
Okay! You'll be stuffed!
别搞那么多，肾亏呀！
Don't do too much, watch your kidneys
你不知道的，豪哥，他的肾早就亏了
Ho, you should know his kidneys are already messed up
一天上几十次厕所的
He has to go pissing ten times a day
你才肾亏呀
Your kidneys are messed up!
他不行了
He can't do it anymore
我好……厉害的！
I am great!
我们给他检查一下
Let me check on him
来吧
Come on
快来帮忙……按着他
Come, help... Hold him down
正点呀……美女
Look! Beautiful girls
来……坐这儿
Come... Sit here
你吃了“伟哥”没有？要不然不能满足我呀
Have you eaten "Viagra" yet? If not, you can't satisfy me
先让我看看你的家伙！
Let me check your pussy first
来啊
Come...
你试过单肠双鲍没有啊？
You have to keep me company tonight
就这样吧，你们慢慢玩吧
Have fun you guys
拜拜，豪哥
Bye, Ho
我送你
I will take you home
我今晚不干你两次我就不叫鸡雄
I have to screw you twice tonight or my name is not Slut Hung
（深圳某地下赌场）
(An underground casino in Shenzhen)
J说话
Jack high
六寸
Six inches
不要
No, go
我不跟了
I fold
我也不跟了
I fold too
我跟
I bet
J说话
Jack high
3寸
3 inches
我跟！再加五寸！
I bet! And rise 5 inches
我跟
I bet
顺子面先下注
Straight high
顺字？没什么大不了！
Straight? It's no big deal
我不知道那张“9”回来没有
I don't know did my "nine" come back yet
小“9”……小“9”，快回来
Nine... come back
它回来了
He is back
十二寸
Twelve inches
我跟
I bet
开牌，来见我“A”一对
Pair of Aces, what about you?
说了小“9”回来了你又不信
I told you my nine is back
我是顺子
I am lucky to have a straight
八“俘虏”！
Full house eight!
又是我赢啊
I win
顺子
Lucky straight!
棒呀…棒呀
Good!
真是不好意思！又是我赢
I am sorry! I won again
发财啦……发财啦
I am rich...
同花面说话
Flush high
梭哈
Show hand
兄弟，忍一忍吧！别白白送钱给他
Pal, hold it! Don't do this
你说什么？你不跟就别唧唧歪歪的
Shut up! You are not gambling, so shut up
不是吧？你还好意思说？
Come on!
你分明骗人家
You want to cheat him!
这是什么？
What is this?
不要啊 …… 不要杀我呀
No... Don't kill me
我把钱全给你 …… 全给你吧
I will give you all my money
不要呀 …… 千万别杀我
Don't kill me
兄弟，你叫什么名字？
What is your name, my friend?
叶世官
Cyclone
张子豪，香港人
Cheung Chi Ho, I am a Hongkie
平时这个时候应该回来了
He should be home by now
他去了哪里呢？
Where did he go?
真没理由
It doesn't make sense
气死我了！
I am very mad!
南叔
Uncle Nam
长官
Officer
你去了哪里啊？我有事找你呀！
Where did you guys go? I am looking for you
等我先猜猜
Let me guess...
你今天是不是煮了猪手等我吃？
You cook knuckle for me?
这几天哪有时间去菜市啊？
I didn't have time to go to the market this couple of days
我查到李仁在银行调了一大笔现金出来
I've found out that Lee En drew a big amount of money from bank
有什么奇怪的？人家做大生意的嘛
So what? Maybe he is doing a big business
不只这样，他还请了不少警卫呢
Not only that he also hired many security guards
这都不代表什么的
So what? It doesn't imply anything
不是的，我总觉得他的儿子一定出意外了
No, I think something did happen to his son
别想那么多了，我找你有事
Stop guessing, I have things for you
有什么事？
What?
有个人想见你
Someone wants to see you
上面叫我与你一起去
My boss told me to go with you
有谁想见我呢？
Who wants to see me?
难道是我梦中情人邓玲茹回来找我？
Is it my dream lover Lady Dan Ling Eu?
邓玲茹就不想见你了
She doesn't want to see you
马君夏就想见见你
But Ma Kun Ha wants to see you
马君夏？
Ma Kun Ha, my ex-boss?
是呀，走吧
Yes, let's go
先拿件衣服
Let me get my jacket first
什么？十亿？
What? One billion?
是啊，没错！
Yes!
的确给了他们十亿
They are given one billion
长官，这么严重的一件事，为什么他们不报警？
Sir, why didn't they contact us? This is a serious crime!
我都问过他，他很难说
I asked Lee but he didn't want to tell the answer
难道有什么特别原因？
Maybe there are some special reasons?
有什么特别原因呢？分明是不相信我们警方
What reasons? They just don't trust the cops
这个有一点可能
Maybe that is the reason
不过最重要的是…
The important thing is...
他在香港是一个有身份有地位举足轻重的人
He is a VlP in Hong Kong
如果报案，事情闹大了
If he called the cops which may screw up the whole thing
他担心他儿子的安全
He worries about his son's life
老实说，这些潮州人最重要的是儿子嘛
Be frank, Chiuchou people value sons very much
何况他又怕被人说闲话
He worries about gossips too
那李巨现在怎么样了？
Where is Lee Gui now?
没事，回家了
At home, he's safe
那他说了什么？
What did he say?
他说鲍鱼很好吃
He said the abalone tasted good
鲍鱼好吃？
He said the abalone tasted good?
李巨说那帮人请他吃鲍鱼
Lee Gui said the kidnappers treated him to abalone
这么多人遭绑架，他这次待遇都算好的了
So many people've been kidnapped before he is the luckiest one
长官，那你找我们做什么？
Sir, what's up?
没办法了，我认识他那么久了
I can't help it I know Lee's family for so long
他把事情告诉我，我不帮他也不是
He told me what happened I can do nothing but to help
但他没有报案啊
He hasn't contacted the police
所以我找你们两个呀
That is why I want you two
为什么，长官？
Why?
他形容绑匪的样子，还有行事那么冷静
He described the look of the kidnapper He works wise and calm
好象是阿南查了多年仍抓不到的张子豪
He may be Cheung Chi Ho the criminal you've followed for ages
阿南，你最了解这个人
Ah Nam, you know this guy very well
我现在告诉你，看你能不能抓到他
I give you a chance now see if you can catch him
是的，长官
Yes, sir
鸡雄
It's Slut Hung
Bonnie
你抓住我的手是不是想学罗家英那样，帮我看掌呀？
You are holding my hand like you are a fortune teller
我不懂看掌啊
I am not a fortune teller
不过你的手好滑
But your hand is very smooth
你想泡我就开口呀
If you want to screw me, just voice out
不过，我胃口好大的呀
Yeah, but I need a lot
我开茶餐厅的，二十四小时服务
I open a convenient store open twenty four hours a day
随便吃不客气
Feel free and help yourself
行了没有？还说是生鸡精！
Are you ready?
不是吧？又要？刚刚才搞完啊
Again? We've just finished
我都告诉你了，我胃口很大的嘛
I told you I am thirsty
一个人住吗？
Do you live by yourself?
不是，和男朋友住
No, I live with my boyfriend
那他一定受不了你的啦
He must not be able to stand you
他都不敢碰我的
He dares not to touch me
你个贱人，我早知道你淫荡的
You bitch, I knew you are bitchy!
不关我事啊
It's not my fault
你还带个男人来我的场子搞？
You even brought a man to my place?
有事慢慢说呀，老兄！
Take it easy, man!
慢慢说？
Shut up
去死吧
Go to hell
小子，这笔账现在怎么算？
Sucker, how are we going to deal with this?
我怎么知道怎么算？
I don't know!
你不知道是吧？我帮你算
You don't know? Let me tell you
你什么地方放进那妞的那里
What you put in that girl's body
就切什么地方
what will be cut off by me
不要呀……不要，救命呀……不要呀
No, help... No! Don't do this!
给个面子呀，大哥
Give me some respect...
我老大是张子豪呀，给个面子，给个面子呀，大哥！
I am with Cheung Chi Ho give us some respects, okay?
给个面子呀！
Give some respect!
你出去
Get out
你在这儿吧
You are here
真想不到我们这么快就见面
I can't believe we can meet again so quickly
那就要多谢你的好兄弟关照了
You must thank your brother
我兄弟呢？他在哪？
Where is he?
抓他过来
Take him out
起来！走！
Get up! Go!
跪下呀！
Get down on your knees!
豪哥，我…
Ho, l...
住嘴！
Shut up
还不多谢官哥？
Say thanks to Cyclone now
多谢我什么？
Thank me for what?
没什么，我张子豪不懂教兄弟
Nothing, l, Cheung Chi Ho don't know how to teach my fellows
难得官哥肯帮我教
Cyclone has disciplined Hung for me
我当然要多谢你啦
Of course I have to thank you
你说什么？
What are you saying?
你这样说就是怪我揍他吧？
You mean you are mad at us for hitting him?
他上了蒙古仔的妞
He screwed Monkey's girl
我不止要揍他
Not only I want to beat him
我还要他把命留下
I have to kill him too
官哥，我们是吃江湖饭的
Cyclone, we are gangsters
命随时可以留下
we are always ready to be killed
如果官哥认为值得的，我无所谓
If Cyclone believes that this is necessary, I don't mind
枪不是这么用的
Gun is not to be used like this
没好处的，无谓浪费子弹
Why waste bullets for nothing?
张子豪，这笔账怎么算？
Cheung Chi Ho, what do you say?
正所谓不知者不罪
It's not his fault since he didn't know that she is your girl
这样吧，官哥
Cyclone, how about this?
我包一封红包给你的兄弟
I will give you and your fellow a red pocket
让他拿个彩头就这么算了吧
to settle this wident, okay?
你说的倒轻松
It's not that easy
如果你老婆被人上了
If your wife sleeps with someone else
那个人封个红包给你，你会怎样？
and that man gives you a red pockets what will you do?
你的话讲的很对
You are absolutely correct
带他进来
Bring them in
进去
Go in
豪哥
Ho
官哥，这里十个人我刚刚找到的
Cyclone, I've just found these ten men
他们个个都跟他的妞干过
They all slept with your girl before
是不是要杀光他们呀？
Do you have to kill them all?
官哥，在你眼中他是条淫虫
Cyclone, you might see him as a slut
但在我眼中
But in my eyes...
他是个跟我出生入死的好兄弟
he is my brother that followed me for ages
他的命比我的性命更重要
His life is more important than mine
如果鸡雄今天换了是你
If you were Slut Hung
我的命一样可以留下
I would have sacrificed for you too
看来我叶世官今天要交你这个朋友
I like you, today l, Cyclone have to make friends with you
由今天开始，我们有福同享
Starting from today let's share what we have!
用你的实力，我的脑筋
T ogether with my brain and your strength
我们合作赚钱
we can make a lot of money
好！我们就一起合作赚钱
Good! We will work together to make big money!
大家忠心义气，发财到底
We will be loyal to each other and make lots of money
（港仔港湾道）
(Harbour Road, Wanchai)
葛先生      葛先生
Mr. Ko Mr. Ko
干什么？
What?
吃饭了
It's time to eat!
有饭都不吃，你那么贱骨头
Why aren't you eating? You creep!
你不玩了？
You're not playing anymore?
用不用这样呀？你输的很少啊
Don't be like this! You only lost a little
你在这里走来走去的干什么？好烦啊，老兄！
Why are you walking around? It's very annoying!
官哥，怎么会那么久？
Cyclone, what takes it so long?
你猜会不会出问题了？
Did something go wrong?
没可能不行的
No way
豪哥，怎么了？
Ho, what happened?
搞定！明天收钱
Okay! We have to collect the money tomorrow!
干杯！
Cheers
鸡雄，你可有不少召妓费了！
Slut Hung, you will have lots of whoring fund
官哥
Cyclone
老兄，不要，不要杀我呀！
Please don't kill me!
不要…… 不要杀我
Pal, don't kill me
官哥，你做什么？
Cyclone, what are you doing?
杀了他呀
I want to kill him
官哥，我们出来混的，要讲道义
Cyclone, we just want money, not life
他的家人愿意付钱，我就愿意放人
If they pay, we will let him go
你错了
Ho, you are wrong
出来混，是要讲道义
As thieves, we have rules
不过，要看怎么用
But you have to know how to apply to it
如果今天为了道义不杀他
If we don't kill him today
可能将来出庭指证我们的……
someday in court he will be witness to nail us
就是他
You understand that?
老兄，不要杀我……我保证不会报警的
Please don't kill me I promised I won't call the cops
你信我，不要杀我……
Believe me, don't kill me
官哥，我知道你讲的对
Cyclone, you have a point
不过一诺千金
But always keep my promise
我答应过收了钱就放人，不可以不守信用
I promised to let him go after I receive the ransom
豪哥，我听你说的
Ho, I will listen to you
有一亿五千万，我叫他在大陆交收
There is 1 50 million to be collected I told him we would collect it in China
我想你和鸡雄明天到上面收钱
I want you and Slut Hung to go tomorrow
好！有钱收我就最开心了
Yeah! I am always happy to get money!
豪哥，我……
Ho, l...
我什么？拿鲍鱼给他吃吧
What? Feed him abalone
还有，天气凉了，拿衣服给他穿吧
The weather is getting cold give him some clothes
来！
Come!
（深圳新闻文化局）
(Shenzhen News and Cultural Council)
家伙带来了没有？
Did you bring it?
那支大的呢？
Did you bring the big one?
不用了吧，我想没什么必要，只拿了小的
I didn't think it's necessary so I only bring the small one
你猜现在是你作主，还是我作主呢？
Are you in charge now?
人家做的是大生意，你猜的着吗？
They have big business, can you guess?
时间到了，还不回去拿？打的少啊？
It's time, go back and get it now! Want to get beaten up?
你来干嘛？
What are you doing?
我来拿枪的
I come to get the guns
用来对付我呀？
Is it for me?
在房里呀，自己拿吧
It's in the room, get it yourself
做什么呀？
What?
那你想做什么呢？
What you want to do?
胸口还通不通呀？
Does your chest still hurt?
走开啦，我有正事要做的
Go away, I have things to do
你还害我不够吗？
Haven't you hurt me enough?
我怎会害你呢？
How did I hurt you?
走开呀！
Go away!
男人我见的多了
I have seen many men
还没见过一个像你一样没用的！
But I've never seen someone so useless like you
算了吧！
Forget it!
你说什么？
What did you say?
我说什么？
What did I say?
难为我每天都那么想你呀
I think about you everyday
现在你见到我连看都不敢看我？
But now you are scared to lay eyes on me
他们都出去了
They are all gone
我都不知道你害怕什么？
I don't know what you are afraid of?
我答应了豪哥嘛
I promised Ho
你只答应了豪哥而已
You only promised Ho
但是豪哥现在都不在这里
But Ho is not here, right?
我很想你呀
I really miss you!
我受不了啦，我要呀
I can't stand it, let's get it on!
你个死荡妇呀
You slut
我不教训你我不叫鸡雄
I must teach you a lesson or my name is not Slut Hung
想不到他们付钱付的那么爽快
I can't believe they will pay that easily
我们这次回乡下盖大楼，吃一辈子都够了
We can go back to our homeland and live happily ever after
官哥，鸡雄那混蛋被你掴了一巴掌居然不回头呀
Cyclone, Slut Hung really is not coming back
那更好，告诉豪哥，少分一份
That is good, I will tell Ho this forget about his share
混蛋！
Bastard!
你找死呀？还敢碰我的妞？
You are dead you still dare to touch my girl?
去死吧！
To hell with you!
不要…
No...
你这淫虫，留条命在世上只会吃贵米
You slut, you are useless
不要呀，官哥
Forgive me, Cyclone
给我一次机会，不要杀我！
Give me one more chance, don't kill me!
你这混蛋那么爱干
You love sex so much
干完一次又一次，你当我假的吗？
One time after another you don't think I care?
官哥，干掉他吧
Cyclone, kill him
不要呀，官哥
No, Cyclone!
给我一次机会，放过我吧
Give me one more chance, please
如果这样都放过你，我的兄弟怎么出来混呀？
How can I let you go? What will my fellows think of me?
如果你杀了我，豪哥……
If you kill me, Ho will...
他会以为你想吃了他那一份
He will think you want to take his share
不要呀！
No!
大不了我不要我那一份，都给你好不好？
I give up my share and you can have it, okay?
放过我吧
Let me go
我现在走了
I am leaving now
谢谢官哥……
Thank you Cyclone...
就算我不杀你，你都要把一些东西留下
I won't kill you but you have to leave me something!
让我向我的兄弟交代
So I can show my fellows my leadership
给我立即回香港
Get your ass back to Hong Kong now
别让我再在这儿见到你
Don't let me see you here again
不然一枪打爆你的头
Or I will kill you
还不谢谢官哥？
Thank Cyclone now!
谢谢官哥，多谢！
Thank you Cyclone!
贱人！
Slut!
细辉
Fai
我肚子有点饿，出去买些烧鹅，卤味和啤酒回来吧
I am hungry go buy some food, and beer too
叫他帮我买一瓶跌打酒吧
Also tell him to buy me a bottle of herbal liquor, please
辉，买一瓶跌打酒回来吧
Fai, buy a bottle of herbal liquor
让那三八擦的
It's for that bitch
长官
Sir
是他打电话的
It's him who made the call
长官，他们全在上面
Sir, they are all upstairs
上去
Let's go
有公安呀
Police
收到
Got it
官哥，有好多公安正上来呀
Cyclone, there are lots of police coming
拿钱从天台那么走
We will escape from the roof with the money
走
Go!
豪哥，你做什么呀？
Ho, what are you doing?
不知道为什么，眼皮一直在跳
I don't know why my tarsal is twitching
妈妈说用一片红色的花瓣贴住眼睛就会没事的了
Mom said you'd put a piece of red petal on it, it'll be okay then
三八！
Stupid!
是真的
It's true!
豪哥
Ho
怎么样？钱收到了吗？
What happened? Did you get the money?
收到
Yes
不过有些事我对不起你
But I did something bad to you
什么事？
What?
鸡雄那混蛋不单又干上蒙古仔的老婆
Slut Hung slept with Monkey's girl again
还报公安，做叛徒举报我们
He also called the cop and tried to turn us in
我不可以放过他
I won't let him get away
慢着，官哥，鸡雄现在在哪里？
Wait, Cyclone where is Slut Hung right now?
让我跟他说
Let me talk to him
我现在都在找他
I am looking for him too
找到他我会摆平他
We will kill him when we find him
官哥，我立即上来
Cyclone, I am coming right now
对不起
Sorry
阿忠
Ah Chung
是，什么事呀豪哥？
Yes, what's wrong, Ho?
鸡雄出了事
Something happened to Slut Hung
立即拿回乡证去深圳
Get your passport we are going to Shenzhen now Okay
阿豪，没事吧？
Ho, is everything okay?
阿豪
Ah Ho...
小姐，有没有见到一个眼睛大大
Ms, have you seen a man with big eyes?
高高瘦瘦的香港人？
He is a man from Hong Kong tall and skinny
没有啊，我没见过呀
No, haven't seen one
豪哥，找了这么久都找不到
Ho, we have been looking for him for so long
不如回去等消息吧
Let's go back and wait for his news
鸡雄就快没命了，快找吧
Slut Hung is about to die, find him!
好象是他
It's him
鸡雄
Slut Hung
豪哥
Ho
真的是他！终于找到了
It's really him! We've found him
鸡雄
Slut Hung
叛徒
Traitor
鸡雄，走呀
Slut Hung, run
不要呀！
No!
鸡雄…
Slut Hung...
豪哥，吃饭吧
Ho, eat something
豪哥
Ho
你们去吧，我不去了
You go, I am not going
我明白的
I understand
豪哥，走啦
Ho, let's go
豪哥，事情闹大了，走啦
Ho, everyone knows now, let's go
走吧，快…
Hurry
走啦…豪哥，快…
Let's go... Ho, Hurry
走呀…
Go...
Go
豪哥，鸡雄死了，我们该怎么办？
Ho, Slut Hung is dead What are we going to do?
是不是就这么算了？
We are not going to let this go, are we?
你少说几句好不好？
Be quiet
我们这么多年兄弟，鸡雄死了难道我不伤心吗？
We have been brothers for years you think I am not sad?
不过，他是该死的
But he deserves it
家有家规！我不会怪叶世官
Rules are rules! I won't blame Cyclone
我只会怪我自己
I will only blame myself
其实整件事都跟你无关
Ho, it is not yourself
关我的事！
It's my fault!
因为是我的兄弟出卖他们
Because my brother was the traitor
算了吧！以后不用再捉鸡雄了
Forget it! We don't have to run after Slut Hung anymore
待他的尸体运回香港之后
Wait until his body is shipped back to Hong Kong
你们替他风光大葬就是了
We will give him a big funeral
豪哥，到房间去吧，我有话想跟你说
Ho, I want to have a word with you
阿豪，你别怪我多事
Ho, I am not nosy
虽然鸡雄确实有点不对
Although Slut Hung was the traitor
但事实上他确实是被叶世官所杀
the fact is, Cyclone did kill him!
我很担心呀
I am worried
担心什么呀
Why?
虽然你答应我不杀人
You promised you won't kill anyone
但是你跟叶世官走在一起
but you are now teamed with Cyclone
你叫我又怎么不担心呢？
How can I not be worried?
如果你真的想我不担心的话
If you don't want me to be worried
答应我，不要再和他一起
promise me, end the partnership with Cyclone, okay?
过两天等他回来之后我跟他讲清楚吧
I will talk to him after he comes back
（西环码头凌晨）
(Pier at Kennedy Town, midnight)
我坐到屁股都快长疮了
My butt is hurting
我肚子饿得快死啦，腰酸背又痛
I am hungry and my back hurts
这袋子又重得要命
This bag is so heavy
重就让我拿好了
Then let me carry it
做一点点事情就说个没完没了的
Only a little thing and you nag so much!
有警察
Police
镇定一点，别看，继续走
Calm down, don't look, keep walking
站住
Hold it
走
Run!
再走就开枪啦
Stop or I will shoot
别胡来……
Hold it
兄弟，你当差不过是我一份工作
Bro, this is only a job for you
拿性命来拼不值得的！
Is it worth to give your life away?
今晚大家当没见过面
Just act like we didn't see each other tonight
你继续巡逻，大家当没事发生过好不好？
You keep on patrolling and just act nothing happened, okay?
好…好，我们从没见过面…
Ok... I didn't see you tonight
镇定一点……别紧张
Calm down... Don't be scared
走……
Go...
妈的！不守信用
Bastard! You didn't keep your words!
别乱来……别乱动啊……
Hold it... Don't move...
看看那个袋子
Look at his bag!
师兄，有好多军火呀！
There are lots of guns!
重案组黄sir ，开门
I'm officer Wong from the Serious Crime Bureau, open the door!
医生，他有没有事？
Doctor, how is he?
暂时来讲没什么事
He is stable right now
不过康复之后就麻烦大了
But he will not recover fully
什么意思？
What do you mean?
按目前的情况来看，即使痊愈之后
The look from right now
下半辈子都要坐在轮椅上
he will spend the rest of his life on wheelchair
姑娘，每隔两个小时给他探热和量血压
Nurse, check his BP and temperature every two hours
叶世官，我们很久没见了
Cyclone, haven't seen you for a long time
我真不明白，你走了这么久干嘛还要回来呢？
I don't understand why do you still want to come back?
你带这么多军火上来干什么？
Where are all these firearms going?
叶世官，你别装傻扮疯呀
Cyclone, stop acting stupid
逃脱的那两个是谁？
Who are the two men that escaped?
他们叫什么名字？现在藏在哪里？
What are their names? Where are they now?
太久了！我差点忘记了你叫“哑狗”
It's been too long! I almost forgot your name Dumb Doggie
但这次有点不同
There is something different this time
根据刚才医生所说
From the doctor
你即使不死，但下半辈子都要坐在轮椅上
he said that you will be on wheelchair for the rest of your life
你别指望再有机会逃脱
You can't escape this time
你最好告诉我们，你带那么军火干什么？
You'd better tell us where all the guns are going?
而且，逃脱了那两个是谁？
Also, who are the two men that escaped?
要是你肯说的话
If you talk
我们会向法庭打一份报告，向法官求情
I will give the court a report and beg the judge for you
怎么样？
What do you think?
好的，不要紧！我们走吧
That's fine! Let's go
反正新案旧案加起来你下半辈子就别妄想可以离开监狱了
You are going to spend the rest of your life in jail anyway
我们走吧
Let's go
想帮你都不行
I can't help you
开门
Open the door
豪哥，现在这样的情况
Ho, from the stand point right now
我们还是离开一会儿比较安全
We should leave for a while
免得官哥他……
In case Cyclone...
你说什么？我老大决不会乱说话的
What are you trying to say? My boss won't confess anything
你以为他是鸡雄呀？
You think he is like Slut Hung?
对不起，豪哥！
Ho, sorry!
阿强这么说都是为了大家的安全而已
Ah Ken just worries about everyone's safety
对不对？
Right?
你说是就是了！
Say whatever you want!
叶世官不是那种人
but Cyclone is not that type of person
阿豪，你还是小心点好
Ho, just be careful
相信我吧！我不会看错人的
Believe me! I won't be wrong
蒙古仔！
Monkey!
什么事，豪哥？
Ho, what is it?
分了钱之后，你带点钱给他大陆的亲人吧
After we split the money bring some to Cyclone's relatives
谢谢豪哥
Thank you Ho
那我老大怎么办？
What about my boss?
让我想想办法
I will think of something
保安科正跟进有刑事记录者不能开计程车的法案
About those who have criminal records cannot become a taxi driver...
因为由于各方面意见不一
Because the two sides can't come to an agreement
我们会再开会研究可行性
They will have another meeting
由于法案通过之后
Because if the law passes
将会令到部分有案底的司机失业
many drive will lose their jobs
所以我们会很小心地处理这个建议
We will treat this matter very carefully
周太太，你女儿上课不太专心
Mrs. Chow, your daughter is not paying attention in school
我希望你能留意一下
Please look into this matter
她会不会花太多时间在明星身上了？
Is she spending too much time on the stars?
她放学之后去做什么粉丝
After school, she goes join that fan club
你真是的，浪费金钱买这种照片
Why do you waste money on useless pictures?
什么事？
What?
黄主任，钟太太来了
Mrs. Chung is here
她现在在外面，要不要……
She is outside, should l...
我知道钟太太是政府高官
I know she is a senior official
但也要守秩序的啊
but she needs to follow our rules too
她来到学校是以家长的身份而已
She comes as a parent only
你不乖呀！老师要见我啊！
You misbehaved so your teacher wants to see me
对不起，妈咪，我知道你很忙
I am sorry I know you are busy
钟太太，董先生正等着你
Mrs. Chung Mr. Tung is waiting to see you
随他等吧
Let him wait
用不用我跟主任说，让你早点见？
Do you want me to let you go in early?
不行！如果连我也不守秩序
No! If I don't follow the rules
我又怎么样要求市民守法呢？
how can I help my fellow citizens?
是的……是的
Right
你们两个走远一点，我跟女儿有秘密要谈
Leave us alone I want to talk to my daughter secretly
是！
Okay!
你要乖啊！妈咪很忙的嘛
You have to behave! Mom is very busy
我不是经常有时间看着你的功课的嘛
I can't always look after you
你自己要勤奋一点，知道吗？
You have to work harder, understand?
你的女儿很乖啊
Your daughter is very good
呵呵！她很顽皮的
No! She is very naughty
小女孩不顽皮就是蠢钝的啦
She is only a little girl being naughty is normal
还是活泼一点好
It's better being naughty than being stupid
喂……是……
Hello... Yes...
当然了，高调一点好
Of course... being high profile is better
让市民知道我们警方也做了很多事的……
Let the citizens know that the police did a lot
好象抓到叶世官了
Looks like they've captured Cyclone
我有枪啊！
I have a gun
你不顾自己也顾下小孩子啊
Even if you don't care about yourself worry about the girl
况且他们站的那么远
They are standing very far
你是什么人
Who are you?
叶世官的朋友
Cyclone's friend
你好大胆呀
How dare you
这句话应该是我说的
I should be the one saying that
女人之中你都算很大胆了
You are the bravest woman I ever met
你不怕我吗？
You are not scared of me?
我是政府官员
I work for the government
为什么要怕你们这些亡命之徒呢？
Why should I be scared of rascals?
好！够正气！
Good!
你想怎么样？
What do you want?
叫你们放了叶世官，你们是一定不肯的了
I want you to free Cyclone but I don't think you will
至少，希望你们不要难为他
At least, treat him good
不要严刑逼供
Don't ever try to use force to make him confess
我们不做这种事的
We won't do that
是你说的呀！其实我这次来绝无恶意的！
You said it! By the way I don't mean my harm
我们只是求财
I just want money
不过我想告诉你
But let me tell you
我们要找你或其他高官实在太容易
It's very easy to find you or any other senior officials
所以，做人留点余地的好
So, always be a little merciful to others
你恐吓我啊？
Are you threatening me?
我没说过呀
I didn't say that
听电话吧
Pick up the phone
喂？
Hello
钟太太，那个人不太对劲
Mrs. Chung something wrong with that man
我们过来好吗？
Should we come help?
照你意思做啦！  好……
Do as you said... Okay...
继续吧
Continue
别当我是傻瓜
You think I am stupid?
好好对待叶世官，要不然我一定教你好看
Treat Cyclone well, or else I'll give you a good lesson!
钟太太，没事吧？
Mrs. Chung, are you okay?
没事
Yes, I am fine
那个人到底是谁？
Who is that man?
一个很不容易应付的人
A tough guy
（北京某会议厅）
(One conference room in Beijing)
是…是
Yes...
我马上派人去办理
I will get someone on it right now
替我接孔其安
Call the Commissioner of Police for me
喂
Hello
喂，董先生，你好！
Hello, Mr. Tung
是……好的，我知道该怎么办了
Yes... Okay, I know what to do
马上替我安排一个记者招待会
Call a press conference right now
我要严厉打击罪案
I want to severely beat crimes!
这个是中央颁发的第三号文件
This came from the government of Mainland China
主犯叫张子豪
The number-one-wanted criminal's name is Cheung Chi Ho
根据文件提示
According to the file
张子豪这个人跟香港多宗持械行劫和绑架案有关
Ho is related to many kidnapping and robbery cases
局长，三号文件还有什么指示呢？
Chief, is there anymore information?
中央指示要各省各市尽量收集他的犯罪证据
Central government will try to collect any of his records from every city
局长，这位是黄局长
Chief, this is Chief Wong
陈科长，你好       董局长
Hello How are you doing?
我们接到指示，要全权接手张子豪的犯罪证据
We got order to take over the investigation of Ho
根据线报，张子豪经常与本地犯罪集团接触
According to the leads Ho's already contacted the local gangs
所以希望黄局长能够尽力协助
So I wish Chief Wong can help us
一定……我们一定会尽全力协助国安局的
Of course, we will try our best to assist
现在我们首先要找到张子豪，尽量监视他
We must find Ho first and surveillance him
一有证据就立刻拘捕他
Once we have hard evidence we will arrest him
是……我们一定会全力打击所有的犯罪份子
Yes, it's time for us to fight back on all the criminals
谢谢你们合作
Thank you for your help
有你们的支持
With your help
我相信很快就能将这个犯罪集团连根拔起
I believe we will be able to uproot this gang
真够肉麻的
Nasty
进来
Come in
什么事
What is it?
钟太太，李警司找你
Mrs. Chung Superintendent Lee is here for you
钟太太，这四位同事会配合原本的四位
Mrs. Chung, these four men will join the original four
二十四小时贴身保护你
to protect you every minute
这是上级的命令
This is an order from above
是吗？
Really?
你们的上级肯定是认为张子豪这么大胆会再来找我？
Your boss believes that Ho will come back for me?
没事的话就最好了
I hope not
万一钟太太有什么事
If anything happens to you
一定会引起社会极度不安
It will cause a disturbance in the society
原来不是疼我！
Oh, this is not for me
原来只是社会的错
It's for the society
钟太太，我们只是按照命令做事而已
Mrs. Chung, we are just doing our job
你们保护好大老板不是更好？
You should worry more about our big boss
我们已经将董先生的保安加到最强
Don't worry
总共有二十二人
we've already sent twenty two men to protect him
踢世界杯呀？这么多人？
Wow, do you need to send that many men?
一个张子豪就弄到满城风雨
Just Ho alone can mess up the whole city!
一天抓不到他，都会引起社会不安
One day we don't catch him it'll cause social unrest
不舒服啊？
You don't feel good?
不怎么为什么，最近总是浑身不舒服
I don't know why, I just don't feel well
而且还整天头痛
and I always have headache
是不是发烧啊？
Do you have a fever?
要不要看医生？
Do you need a doctor?
不用了！吃点药应该没事的了
No, I will be fine
吃完药之后到房间休息下吧
Go rest after taking some medicine
阿忠还没回来？
Where is Ah Chung?
他们去了哪里？
Where did they go?
我见他们去帮我买点东西
I tell them to buy something for me
豪哥……阿嫂
Ho... Sister-in-law
今天拜关帝吗？
Are you going to worship the God of Kwan?
不是拜关帝
No
自从阿雄死了之后
Since the death of Slut Hung
我每晚都梦见他满身鲜血
I always dream of him with his body covered with blood
他还说死的好惨，一个人什么都没
And he said he doesn't deserve to die
所以我叫阿忠买点东西烧给他
So I tell Ah Chung to buy some paper money and burn it to him
难怪有几晚睡醒了不见你
No wonder I don't see you when I wake up in the middle of the night
我怕的睡不着，所以到客厅坐一会
I can't sleep so I went to sit in the living room
怎么不叫醒我陪你？
Why didn't you wake me up to keep you company?
一个人没的睡，总好过两个人没的睡
I didn't want to bother you!
我们别说这些了，先将东西烧给阿雄吧
Forget it let's burn something for Slut Hung
阿忠，那是什么？
What is it, Ah Chung?
吹气娃娃！
Sex doll!
我跟鸡雄一场兄弟，都没送过他什么
Being his brother for so long I never buy him anything
刚才路过看到，就买来送给他
I saw this, so I bought it for him
这个吹气娃娃真没买错，最合他的心意了
This sex doll fits him, he will love it
烧给他？他不是那么好色
But if he was not such a slut
就不会搞到连命都赔上了
he would not have been killed
阿豪，你还记不记得你答应过我什么？
Ho, remember what you've promised me?
当然记得了
Of course!
不杀人，赚够了钱就收手
No killing, and quit after making enough money
陪你去尼斯湖看水怪
And take you to England to watch sea monster
我知道你真的没杀过人
I know you didn't kill anyone
但阿雄他真的死了
but Slut Hung is dead
钱你有了，你还想要什么呢？
You already made enough money what else do you want?
你知不知道你每天出去之后
Do you know every time when you leave
我都好担心你
I am really scared
我不知道你会发生什么事
I don't know what will happen?
我真的不想你变成第二个鸡雄
I don't want you to end up like Slut Hung
我真的好辛苦，你知道吗？
I am really worried, do you know that?
没事的！前两天我还在想有什么生意适合我们去做
Don't worry! I am thinking what other business we should get into
那不如开车行啦！反正你那么喜欢车
Car dealer! Since you love cars so much
你喜欢开车行就开车行吧
Whatever you like
豪哥，有人找你
Ho, here is someone for you
你是豪哥吗？
You are Ho?
有何贵干？
What?
我叫柠檬头，今天早上才从赤柱监狱出来
I am Lemon Head, I just got out from the jail today
有张字条是官哥叫我给你的
This note is from Cyclone
拿去喝茶吧
This is for you
多谢豪哥
Thank you Ho
什么东西？
What is it?
是叶世官写的！他叫我们救他
Is from Cyclone! He wants us to save him
那你怎么办？
So?
怎么救呢？说的容易
How? It's not that easy
他在赤柱里面呀
He is in jail
我们没办法呀！难道炸了赤柱啊？
There is nothing we can do! Want us to blow up the jail?
你又说废话了！
Nonsense!
让我做完这件事完成了心愿之后
This is the last job I am going to do
我们就开车行重新来过
After that we will be car dealer and start over
我不知道你是怎么想的
I don't know what you are thinking
阿雄是他杀的，你还要去救他？
He killed Slut Hung and you want to save him?
我们这行，义气为先
We have rules
你不会明白的
and you won't, understand it
放心啦！不会有事的
Don't worry! It will be fine
我知道你决定了的事没人可以改变
I know I can't change your mind
你自己小心点啦
Just be careful
阿忠
Ah Chung
明天跟我去大陆一趟
Go with me to Mainland China tomorrow
我要炸掉赤柱监狱
I want to blow up the jailhouse in Stanley
我们从各方面得到的资料
From all the leads we received
证明了张子豪这次是为了购买炸药而来的
which proofs that Ho comes to buy explosive
至于数量有多少和什么时候运到香港的日期还不知道
But we don't know how much or when it'll arrive in Hong Kong
一有进一步的消息就会马上通知你们
We will contact you as soon as we have more information
他出来了
It's him
老婆，还没来的？我在火车站外面
Honey, where are you? I am outside the train station
我和你妈妈在喝茶，刚送了她回家
I have tea with your mother I just took her home
我马上过来了
I will be there in no time
好的
Okay
你等我吧
Wait for me
张子豪
Cheung Chi Ho
你都算了不起的了
You are good
南叔，我怎么了不起呀？
Uncle Nam, why did you say that?
难道坐火车也犯法吗？
Is it illegal to ride the train?
难道抓你要选日子啊？
Do we have to pick a day to arrest you?
南叔，你抓了我也没用的
Uncle Nam, arresting me won't do you any good
每次都是白做的啦
It will just waste your time
未必的！有志者事竞成
There's a wish, there's a way
走吧
Let's go
长官，这样做怕不怕出事？
Sir, is this right?
不用怕！这个是特别个案，我是直接向上级交代的
Don't worry! This is special I will report to the chief
你们放心去做吧
Just do it
有什么事我负责
I'll be responsible for it
这次由我来吧，我忍这混蛋好久了
Let me do it, I am sick of him
好的
Okay!
没问题
No problem
干什么？哑了啊？
Talk! What? You can't talk?
长官……
Sir...
张子豪，你别耍花样了
Cheung Chi Ho, no more tricks
你有没有绑架李巨和葛炳丹？
Did you kidnap these two men, Lee and Ko?
你在大陆买了这么多炸药回来想干什么？
You bought a load of explosive in China, what do you want?
我都不知道你们说什么
I don't know what you are saying
我没见过炸药，也没绑架任何人
I've never seen any explosive or kidnapped anyone before
有人被绑架吗？
Did someone get kidnapped?
我看新闻没看到的
It wasn't on the news
拉他起来
Hold him up
说不说？说呀
Confess it or not?
别打头
Don't hit the head
你说不说啊？
Do you want to talk?
你合作点，就大家都不用这么麻烦
Just cooperate and there will not be any trouble
抽只烟吧
Smoke
你不合作也不要紧
It's fine with me if you don't cooperate
虽然现在不够证据
Although there is not enough evidence
但这件事是真的
everybody knows
你不说的话就别怪我帮不到你
If you don't talk don't blame me for not helping you
我出了这个门口之后，我不知道他们会怎么对你
I don't know what they will do after I leave this room
既然你不用我帮
Ok, you don't want my help
祝你好运
Then, good luck
我就看看你嘴巴硬还是我的棍子硬
Let's see which is tougher Your mouth or my rod
阿豪，你怎么样？
Ho, how are you?
我跟你们说，我现在来担保我的当事人张子豪
I am here to bail Cheung Chi Ho
同时，我会保留一切追究你们殴打我当事人的责任
Also I want to file a charge for abusing violence to my client
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
大律师，你别这么大声说话！你说担保就担保啊？
Be quiet, lawyer Who told you that you can bail him?
不准担保？我想问下你们，你们告他什么罪？
Why can't I bail him out? What is his charge?
想不到告他什么罪啊？
You don't know yet?
用不用扣留他四十八小时让你们想清楚？
Do you want to hold him 48 hours to think up one?
张太太，我们现在出去办理担保手续
Mrs. Cheung let's go finish the bailing process
打开它啦！
Release him
傻豹，放了他
Pink Panther, release him
谢谢
Thank you
我都说了你白做的啦
I told you that you are wasting your time
出来了
Here they come...
张先生，警方为什么拘捕你呢？
Mr. Cheung, why did the police arrest you?
我都不知道他们为什么要抓我
I don't know why
但有点奇怪，他们谁也不抓
Don't you feel weird?
却抓了你这么多次
The police arrested you many times
你知不知道什么原因呢？
Why?
他们分明针对我
They are picking on me
一会说我持枪，一会说我行劫
They blame me for everything
一会又说我绑票
They say I am a kidnapper too
他们分明针对我
They just don't like me
张先生，那你对这件事有什么看法呢？
Mr. Cheung, what do you think?
会不会追究？
Will you claim a loss?
是啊，会不会追究？
Will you?
我是一个良好市民
I am a good citizen
怎么追究啊？
How can I go against the cops?
我跟他们很合作的
I always cooperate with the cops
但是他们却把我打成这样
But they abused violence on me
伤势真的很严重
He is really beaten badly
张太太，张先生伤的那么严重，你心痛吗？
Mrs. Cheung, are you sad that your husband got beaten up like this?
他被警方打成这样，你说我心不心痛呢？
He got beaten up by the police what do you think?
我不敢说他是个百分百的好人
I can't say he is a hundred percent good man
但警方如果有证据的话，可以随时告他
But if the police really have hard evidence feel free to sue him
要不然根本就不应该将他打成这样
If not, they shouldn't beat him up like this
对不起，我赶着带张先生去看医生
Sorry everyone, we need to take Mr. Cheung to the doctor
张先生  拍张照啦
Mr. Cheung, a picture please
请让开……
Move
又被那混蛋大摇大摆的走出去
The bastard fled again
长官，原来他一早就约好记者在警察局门口等他
Chief, he called the press to wait for him outside the station
还拉起衣服给记者照相
He also lift up his shirt for pictures
有没有搞错啊？
Is he sick?
明天报纸又会大肆渲染了
Wait until tomorrow's newspaper we'll be criticized again
说我们警方使用暴力
It will say that he police abuse violence
没办法的长官
Sir, there is nothing we can do
明知道他私买炸药
We know that he buys explosive illegally
我们不能起诉他，所以下手当然重了一点
but we can't press charges on him
难道等他拿到炸药之后炸死人再动手吗？
Do we have to wait until he kills someone with those explosive?
大家听着
Listen, everyone
长官
Sir
那些记者怎么报道，全部不用担心
No matter what the press says you don't have to worry
我会搞定
I will deal with them
这是张子豪出入的场所
This is Cheung Chi Ho's hide out
大家要二十四小时监视
I want a surveillance team there 24 hours a day
看看他买回的炸药会不会放在这些地方
Check and see whether he hides the explosive there
马上行动
Let's get working
Yes,sir！
Yes, sir
巨人呼叫宝贝，收到吗？
Giant calls Baby one, copy?
宝贝一号收到
Baby one copies
你那边什么状况呀？
Did you see anything?
这里一切正常
Everything is normal
巨人呼叫宝贝二号
Giant to Baby 2, copy?
宝贝二号收到
Baby 2 copies
你那边什么状况呀？
What is the situation there?
风平浪静
Very quiet
巨人呼叫宝贝三号
Giant to Baby 3, copy?
宝贝三号收到
Baby 3 copies
你那边什么状况呀？
What is your situation?
没状况
Nothing
巨人呼叫宝贝四号
Giant to Baby 4, copy?
宝贝四号收到
Baby 4 copies
你那边什么情况呀？
What is your situation?
没什么情况
Nothing
巨人呼叫宝贝五号，你那边什么状况呀？
Giant to Baby 5, what is your situation?
没状况
Nothing
长官，你猜他们会不会将那些炸药放到其他地方呢？
Sir, do you think the explosive will be somewhere else?
不会的！南叔跟了他们这么久
No! Uncle Nam is being on his tail for so long
很清楚张子豪的个性
he understands Ho very well
南叔，有情况
Uncle Nam, something is up
宝贝一号呼叫巨人
Baby 1 to Giant
巨人收到
Giant copies
宝贝一号，你那边什么事呀？
Baby one, what is it?
我见到一辆货车正开过来
I see a van coming
他们将货物搬进屋内
They unload the van inside the house
我们让不让车离开？
Should we let the van leave?
记下车牌让它走
Write down the license number and let it go
继续保持联络
Keep contact
宝贝一号收到
Baby 1 copies
宝贝一号呼叫巨人
Baby 1 to Giant
我看见张子豪出现
I see Cheung Chi Ho
南叔，别乱来，等他进去
Uncle Nam, wait, let him go in first
知道
Got you
这次一定要让他人赃并获
We must have him this time
南叔，你给我盯紧他
Uncle Nam, keep your eyes on him
一见到他进入屋内，马上拘捕他
Once he goes inside then we will arrest him
知道
Got it
他没停车呀！还继续开车走了
He didn't stop! He continues driving
小新
Sunny
收到线报，仓库里面可能是他们在深圳接洽回来的炸药
The lab report shows that the sample is explosive
那我们怎么办？
What should we do?
如果那真是烈性炸药
They said the explosive is strong and dangerous
就很危险，如果爆炸就大件事了
If the explosive goes off there will be big trouble
我们可以先疏散附近的居民的嘛
We can evacuate the buildings first
不行！疏散会引起公众恐慌
No! It will create a mess
为了大众安全
For the citizen' safety
拼一拼，马上通知飞虎队采取搜捕行动
Stop waiting! Call the S.D.U.
是
Yes, sir
什么状况？
What is the situation now?
立即行动
Tell them to get ready
行动
Action!
糟了！
Shit!
别动！
Don't move!
走！
Go!
真的是炸药！
They are explosives
十几箱！最少几百公斤
Ten boxes! It's over hundreds of kilos
李sir，黄sir在那里找到八百公斤炸药
Officer Lee, Officer Wong discovered 800 kilos of explosive
还好成功了
Good job
豪哥，那批炸药被他们找到了
Ho, they discovered the explosive
我看他们一定不会就此罢休的
Look like they are not going to stop
迟早都会来抓我们
They will come for us soon
来就来咯，抓我们？
Let them come! I am not scared!
他们能起诉我们吗？
They can't charge me with anything
阿豪，你要小心点
Ho, just be careful
他们有证据就一早来抓我们啦
If they had evidence they would have arrested me
真是吃屎狗！走着瞧
Wait and see dicks!
迟早给他们个炸弹尝尝！
They will soon taste the power of my bombs
不是说烧烤吗？还不去买东西？
Didn't you say you want to barbecue?
你想吃什么？我买给你
What do you want to eat? I go to buy it
随便啦！买多点大家一起吃
Whatever! Just buy more than enough
早点回来
Hurry back
我们没了这批炸药，要找一个炸弹
We have no more explosive so we need a bomb
炸弹？我们去哪找一个炸弹回来啊？
Bomb? Where are we going to find a bomb?
炸弹就是钟方安心
The bomb is Mrs. Chung
他们要跟我们玩，我们就玩大一点
They want to play with me then I just have to show hand
喂…照你的意思去做
Hello... we will do as you said
好…就这样
Okay... That is it
囡囡 囡囡
Baby...
吃早餐啦
Breakfast is ready
囡囡，别再玩了，吃早餐了，要上学了
Baby, stop playing, breakfast is ready
钟太太
Mrs. Chung
还认得我吗？
Do you remember me?
你好吗？
Mrs. Chung, how are you?
我有八个保镖的
I have eight bodyguards
你别乱来
Don't do anything stupid
识相的马上走
I think you should leave now
只有四个而已，我早打发他们走了
You've only four I told them to leave already
她只是个小女孩，这件事别牵涉到她
She is only a little girl leave her out of this
妈咪，你说什么啊？
Mom, what are you saying?
把女儿还给我
Give me back my Mandy
钟太太，我最讨厌用暴力了
Mrs. Chung, I hate violence
但我这次没的选择
But this time I have no choice
你逃不掉的
You won't get away
全香港的警察都不会放过你
The entire police force won't let you get away with this
我知道！所以我想你跟我走
I know! So I want you to go with me
不可能！
Impossible!
你说呢？
What do you think?
小女孩是无辜的，我不想伤害她
The girl is innocent, don't hurt her
你别乱来
Don't do anything stupid
你不跟我走，我就一枪干掉她
I will kill her right now if you don't come with me
我不会给你威胁到的
I am not scared of you
是吗？
Really?
好…你放了她，我跟你走
Okay... Let her go first I will go with you
我们一屋都是女人
My whole family is female
你不用怕呀
You don't have to worry
我只是想救我的兄弟而已
I just want to save my buddy
你都算了不起了，这么快找到了我的军火
You guys are something you captured my explosive in no time
不然的话我早就炸掉赤柱监狱了
Otherwise, I was going to blow up the jail
你真是大胆
You are mad
天大地大我最大
I don't care
胜者为王败者为寇
All I care about is my victory
就算你抓了我，他们也不会放叶世官的
Even if you kidnap me they won't release Cyclone
走着瞧
We will see
不放的话
If they won't release Cyclone
就算你倒霉了
then it will be your unlucky day
囡囡    妈咪！
Mandy Mom!
张子豪
Cheung Chi Ho!
钟太太，你没事吧？
Mrs. Chung, are you okay?
别跑
Stop
大嫂
Sister-in-law...
豪哥…
Ho...
怎么这么迟？
Why are you so late?
我们来的时候，收到消息，警察到处在找我们
On our way here I heard the cops are looking for us
所以我叫你们来大家商量下
So we need to talk
豪哥，依我看，这次他们一定要整死我们的
Ho, this time the police are putting us to a dead end
阿豪，那我们现在怎么办？
Ho, what should we do?
不用担心
Don't worry
阿强，趁他们没出通缉令之前
Ken, before they issue a warrant
看来我们要避一避
we should go hide for a while
不如一起去海南岛避一避
Ho, let's go to hide in Mainland China
不行！他们的目标是我
No! I am their target
如果你们两个跟着我，有什么事会连累你们
If I go with you I will get you into troubles
只剩你一个人我们不放心啊
Ho, we can't leave you here
我会自己照顾自己的
Don't worry! I can take care of myself
你们有什么打算？
What are you guys going to do?
我可以去柬埔寨找我叔叔，住上几个月
I am going to stay with my uncle in Cambodia
阿强，一起啦！
Come with me, Ken
无所谓呀！反正我是孤儿
Why not? I am single
哪里都一样的！
Everywhere is the same to me
去到哪里都好，记住给我个电话
No matter where you guys go give me a call
小心点
Be careful
放心！你保重，我们没事的
Don't worry! We will be fine
保重！豪哥，我们先走了
Take cares, Ho, bye
豪哥，走了
Ho, bye
阿豪，我有一点担心，我有种不详的预兆
Ho, I am worried I have a bad feeling about this
没事的！你神经过敏而已！
It will be fine!
我到内地避一阵子就没事的了
I will just hide in Mainland China for a while
那我们不是很久见不到面啦？
Then we can't see each other for a long time?
我会打电话给你的
I will call you
sir，他现在在火车站啊
Sir, he is at the train station
看来他想搭火车回大陆
Look like he is going to Mainland China
我们是不是在罗湖站截他呢？
Should we stop him at Lo Wu Station?
你们先跟着，等我消息
Just follow him first
收到
Got it
孔sir，刚刚收到消息张子豪正去火车站
Commissioner, we hear that Ho is going to the train station
看来想回大陆
Looks like he is going to Mainland China
回大陆？
Mainland China?
如果要抓他，最好在过关的时候抓他
The best time to arrest him is when he is at the custom
有多少成把握抓到他？
Do we have enough evidence to arrest him?
一半一半
Half
你先出去，我考虑下
Let me think about it
yes sir
Yes, sir
喂
Hello
陈科长，那张当票好多次都不能断当
Mr. Chen, we have a hard time arresting this man
你有什么意见？
What do you think?
要不要我们那张当票？
Can you finish the job for us?
好！等我们来处理他，让他进来吧
Okay! We will deal with him let him come into China
好！就这样决定
Okay! It's deal
老婆，当你看到这段录象带的时候，我已经回到大陆
Honey, when you see this tape I am on my way to China
香港我不能再立足了
I can't set foot in Hong Kong anymore
大陆我想可能还有一线生机
China may be my last chance
我没什么牵挂
I don't have much to worry about
唯一不放心的就是你和我妈妈
Just only you and my mother
好好照顾她老人家
Take good care of my mother
我买给你的房子汽车，快点贱价卖掉
The houses and car I bought you sell it quickly at any price
如果我被他们抓到
If they capture me
他们一定会冻结我所有的资产
they will freeze all my money
卖了得到的钱，要好象藏野种一样
Hide all the cash
雷劈都别拿出来
Don't take it out unless it's necessary
还要小心被人趁火打劫
Someone may seek chance to rob you
谁说花钱能救到我的，你千万不要相信
Don't trust anyone who says that money can save me
这次，我面对的不是黑社会
This time, I am not going against a gang
而是整个政府
I am going against the whole government
不可能收买的了
You can't bride the government
也不可能和他们斗
You can't beat it too
我只希望可以逃脱
I just wish that I can escape
如果我逃脱的话，我会跟你一生一世
If I can get away I will live with you forever
如果我被人抓了
If I get arrested
不需要等我
You don't have to wait for me
就算我不被枪毙，都不知道会坐牢到坐什么时候
Even if they're not going to kill me I will be in jail for decades
他们是不会放过我的
They won't let me get away
我爱你！
I love you!
永远爱你！
I love you forever!
将旅行证件拿出来
Document please
你香港人？
You are from Hong Kong?
从哪来的？
Where?
皇岗口岸
From Wanggang
去哪儿？
Where are you going?
去蛇口那边看看厂
T o go to Shikuo to check out my factory
差不多两个礼拜没去过了
Haven't been there for two weeks
走吧   谢谢
Go Thank you
什么事？
What is it?
国安局的
I am from the National Security Council
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
姜沛元
Cheng Pu Yeu
证件呢？
Document?
做什么生意？
What type of business are you in?
古董家私！
Antique furniture
很好啊！
Not bad!
张子豪，我找你很久了
Cheung Chi Ho I am looking for you for a long time
带他走！
Take him away